[Music]
fy 22 was very challenging for icici
lombard the insurer saw high covert
related claims faced growth headwinds in
the motor segment and the merger with
bharti axa weight on financials however
q1 earnings indicate that fy23 could be
a year of revival the growth and motor
segment is set to rebound with improved
volumes while the revision in
third-party motor tariff rates is not in
line with claims inflation and is also
below the industry expectations higher
penetration benefits can outweigh the
pricing issue to some extent also icici
lombard has made huge investments to
grow its retail health agency channel
and added around thousand head counts in
the past one year consequently
management expects growth in retail
health premium to accelerate in the next
few quarters as the agency managers
start getting more productive moreover
there will be operating synergies and
cost savings from the merger since party
acts are operated at higher expense
ratio this scope of improving operating
efficiency by reducing overheads whether
it's branch cost branding or marketing
costs management expects annualized
synergy benefits of 200 crores in fbi 23
which it plans to reinvest to grow the
business progressive reforms and
regulatory changes would also aid
business growth icici lombard's gdpi
increased by 28 on a year-on-year basis
in q1 f by 23 compared to industry
growth of 23 in the same period
consequently its overall market share
improved to 9.9 by june end the
acquisition of bharti axa added to
market share gains growth in the premium
segment was driven by motor and health
insurance segment motor insurance which
is the largest segment for icici lombard
saw growth in line with the industry and
it's maintained its leadership with a
market share of 11.3 percent in an
interesting development icici lombard is
readjusting its motor vehicle portfolio
away from private cars given the pricing
competition instead it plans to focus on
growing the cv segment accordingly the
proportion of cvs in the motor insurance
mix increased to 24.6
in q1 of fy23 from 16.6 in q1 of f by
22. health insurance saw robust growth
in fy 22 while retail health growth has
moderated growth in group health and
better pricing led to the overall growth
of insurance segment commercial segments
like property and casualty saw a healthy
14 yoi growth largely in sync with the
economic environment icici lombard's
combined ratio which is a measure of an
insurance company's profitability
declined two hundred and four point one
percent in q1 fy 23 from 123.5
in q1 fy 22 thereby reducing the
underwriting loss the combined ratio of
above 100 indicates that the insurer is
paying out more money in claims and
operating expenses more than what it
receives in premiums combined ratio is
the sum of loss or claims ratio and
expense ratio barring the motor od
segment claims ratio improved across all
segments but bulk of improvement in loss
to claims ratio was driven by health
segment which saw claims ratio fall 74
in q1f by 23 from 148 in q1 of fy22 the
expense ratio also declined by 210 basis
points yy which remained higher than the
precovered levels of below 30 percent
the higher expense ratio is mainly due
to the merger with bharti axa that
operated at a much higher expense ratio
and also because of increased
investments in the distribution channels
do investment income decline it's more
than compensated for the underwriting
loss leading to a profit in q1 fy 23.
now due to subdued capital markets
unrealized loss stood at 582 crores as
of june end icici lombard's roe declined
to 15 in q1 fy 23 from around 20
in the previous fiscal years given that
it wants to keep investing and grow the
book a bit faster roe will continue to
be in mid teens going forward as per the
management obviously investment should
lead to better underwriting performance
in the future at the current market
price of around 1240 rupees icici
lombard is trading at a pricey valuation
of 6.4 times trailing book value which
is undoubtedly very rich however its
premium valuation will sustain given
market leading share in a secular growth
sector fairly diversified product mix
strong multi-channel distribution
network solid technological prowess and
strong solvency profile and healthy
profitability following the merger with
bharti axa parent icici bank stake in
the subsidiary has come down from over
51 to 48 post the deal now this has
implications as icici bank will have to
bring the stake down to 30 over a period
or increase it to above 50 as per
regulatory requirement now in september
2020 the government gave icici bank
three years to comply with this
regulation we do not see icici banks
selling 18 equity stake in an icici
lombard in all likelihood it may
increase the stake once again to beyond
50 within the stipulated time
therefore any weakness in the stock
price due to speculation of the supply
overhang should be used as an
opportunity by long-term investors to
add the stock
[Music]
you